Businesses and Professions Collection 0007.002.004
Jewish Historical Society of Greater Hartford
- Series IV: Professions
  - Professions/Legal/Research Paper/Author Unknown/A Separate Elite: Jewish Lawyers, the Legal Profession, and the Jewish Community, no date, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Medical/Historical Museum of Medicine and Dentistry founded by Dr. Leonard Menczer., undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Medical/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Mental Health/Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Musicians, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Nursing, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Nursing/Jewish Nursing Project, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Pharmacists, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Photographers/drescher, Yosefa, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Pilots, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Policemen, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, before 1940, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1940s, 1940-1949 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1950s, 1950-1959 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 1990s, 1990-1999 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Politicians, 2000s, 2000-2009 (Box 4)
  - Professions/Sports, see also Sports and Hall of Fame Collection, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Storytellers, undated (Box 4)
  - Professions/Veterinarians, undated (Box 4)
- Series V: Oversize
  - Home Circle Stores/Advertisements, 1940s; Supermarket circulars; Home Circle Stores.
    Full-page circulars advertising sales and prices at Home Circle Stores grocery stores from the 1940s.
    Businesses -- Grocery
  - Photo Series I: Business & Professions Photographs: A-C
    - Berman Abrahams Harnessmaking, undated (Box 1)
    - Agdish, Nathan/Junk Peddler, undated (Box 1)
    - Aircraft Pharmacy (Samuel H. Cohen), undated (Box 1)
    - Aishberg's Shoes, undated (Box 1)
    - Albany Cash Market, undated (Box 1)
    - Aladdin shop (Emma Perlstein Cohen), undated (Box 1)
    - American Coal, undated (Box 1)
    - Arsenal Bread Shop, undated (Box 1)
    - S. Bacharach Grocery, undated (Box 1)
    - Balgley & Co. photographers, undated (Box 1)
    - R. Ballerstein & Co. Millinery, undated (Box 1)
    - Barbers, undated (Box 1)
    - Bassoks Clothing Store, undated (Box 1)
    - Bergen Bros Auto Tire Co., undated (Box 1)
    - S. Berman Tailor, undated (Box 1)
    - E. Berman Dry Good Store (Elias Berman), undated (Box 1)
    - Big Lion Food Market, taken during 1936 flood. (Harry Reuben, George Reuben, Abe Cohen (Box 1)
    - Blue Hills Delicatessen (Ossie Ospipowitz), undated (Box 1)
    - D. Blumenthal Cloaks, Millinery, undated (Box 1)
    - Bonner & Preston Co. OVERSIZE, undated (Box 1)
    - Cantarow's Drug Store, see also Cantarow family in People, people oversize and people super oversize, undated (Box 1)
    - Capitol Tobacco Co., undated (Box 1)
    - Casey-Folsom Automotive/Ann Street, 1962 (Box 1)
    - Charles St. Chicken Market, undated (Box 1)
    - Cheap John (John Finkelstein; see also Finkelstein's Men’s and Boy’s Outfitters, undated (Box 1)
    - Chinitz Grocery Store (Harry and Rose Chinitz), undated (Box 1)
    - City Coal, undated (Box 1)
    - J.M. Cohn Coal Company, undated (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Grocers' and Marketmen’s association, 1953, undated (Box 1)
    - Copaco (Herman Bercowetz) see also Farming Collection, undated (Box 1)
    - Crockett, Philip, dry goods peddler in Maine, undated (Box 1)
    - Crown Market, undated (Box 1)
    - Crystal Barbershop (Jack Molans, Louis Kosoff), undated (Box 1)
- Photo Series II: Business & Professions Photographs: D-F
  - H.D. Daniel (Men’s Clothing), undated (Box 2)
  - Davidson, Osher, Fruit and Vegetable Peddler, undated (Box 2)
  - Davidson and Leventhal, undated (Box 2)
  - Davison Scrap Iron (Morris Davison), undated (Box 2)
  - Drug store, unidentified, Maxwell’s? 1930s (Box 2)
  - Dworski Dry Goods, undated (Box 2)
  - East Hartford Custom Tailor (Samuel Kovarsky), undated (Box 2)
  - East Side Candy Store (Joseph Wiegel), undated (Box 2)
  - East Side Department Store, undated (Box 2)
  - Eblen’s, undated (Box 2)
  - Elite Studio, undated (Box 2)
  - Empire Delicatessen, 1920s (Box 2)
    Scoler, Eli
  - Epstein’s Crockery and Hardware (Morris and Abraham Epstein), undated (Box 2)
  - Feinblum Music Store (Joseph Feinblum), undated (Box 2)
  - Fine Drug Store, undated (Box 2)
  - Fine Drug Store, see also OVERSIZE, undated (Box 2)
  - Finkelstein’s Men’s and Boy’s Outfitters (John Finklestein; see also Chap John), undated (Box 2)
  - First National Stores (Morris Joseloff), undated (Box 2)
  - Fisher’s Ladies Apparel, undated (Box 2)
  - Freund Meat Market (Simon Freund), undated (Box 2)
  - Friedman’s Dry Goods Store, undated (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co. see also Fox family collection, undated (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./fire damage sale, 1870? (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Buildings/406-410 Main Street, 1880 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Buildings/956-976 Main Street, 1896-1917 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Buildings/956-972 Main Street/Fire and rubble, 1917 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Buildings/956-972 Main Street/Fire aftermath, 1917 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Buildings/1918 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Executives, 1953 (Box 2)
  - G. Fox & Co./Expansions, 1940s and later, 1940-1949 (Box 2)
- Photo Series III: Business & Professions Photographs: G-J
  - Grocery Stores, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3)
  - H. Gerstein, Manufacturer of Ladies Dresses, Lass Setting Store; see also Labinger and Gerstein, undated (Box 3)
  - Gitlen Motor Sales (Herbert Gitlen), undated (Box 3)
  - Gloria Gay Dress Shop (Nathan Myerson), 1947; 1 photo (Box 3)
  - Glotzer & Glotzer Furs, undated (Box 3)
  - K. Goldberg Coal and Feed, undated (Box 3)
  - Goodman, Sam, vegetable peddler, undated (Box 3)
  - Good Samaritan Drug Store, undated (Box 3)
  - J. Gorphine, undated (Box 3)
  - Greenbaum Drug Store (Moses Greenbaum), undated (Box 3)
  - Herman Gross, wholesale bottle dealer, undated (Box 3)
  - L.B. Hass & Co. Tobacco, undated (Box 3)
  - Handler, David, tires and bicycle accessories, undated (Box 3)
  - H. Harris, wallpaper and paints, undated (Box 3)
  - Harris Express Co. (Philip Harris), undated (Box 3)
  - L. C. Harris Pharmacy, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford businesses on CD, undated (Box 3)
  - Hartford Live fish Market (W. Schwartz), undated (Box 3)
  - A. and S. Hartman Leaf Tobacco, undated (Box 3)
  - Hebrew book Store (Jechiel Spiro), undated (Box 3)
  - Hebrew Market (David Matts), undated (Box 3)
  - Hellmann Drug Store (Anton Hellman), undated (Box 3)
  - Hellman's Meat Market, undated (Box 3)
  - Hirshberg Grocery, undated (Box 3)
  - Hirshberg & Samuels, shoes, undated (Box 3)
  - Hoffman brothers, paints and wallpaper (Raymond and Joseph Hoffman), undated (Box 3)
  - Holtz Portrait Studios, undated (Box 3)
  - Home Circle Stores, undated (Box 3)
  - Honiss Oyster House, undated (Box 3)
  - Hotel Perl (Abe Perlstein), undated (Box 3)
  - Hotel Oxford, undated (Box 3)
  - J. Hurwitz Furniture, undated (Box 3)
  - Imperial Photographic Studio (Isaac Pasternack), undated (Box 3)
  - Israel Gift Shop (Joseph and grace Sherman), undated (Box 3)
  - Jacobs Ice Cream and soda water, undated (Box 3)
  - Jainchill & Labinger Cigars, undated (Box 3)
  - H. Jonas Groceries, undated (Box 3)
- Photo Series IV: Business & Professions Photographs: K-L
  - Kahn's grocery (Henry Kahn), undated (Box 4)
  - Kamin’s 5 & 10, undated (Box 4)
  - Kaplan Shoe Store (David Kaplan), undated (Box 4)
  - Karp, Harry, dry goods peddler, undated (Box 4)
  - Karp, Harry, grocery store, Hartford, undated (Box 4)
  - Karp, Harry, shoe store, Bristol, undated (Box 4)
  - Karp, Harry, Karp’s Outlet, Hartford, undated (Box 4)
  - Kashmann's Specialty Market, undated (Box 4)
  - Kashmann's Specialty Market/enlargement in drawer, undated (Box 4)
  - Kashmann's Store (Clothing), undated (Box 4)
  - Katzenstein's Meat Market, undated (Box 4)
  - M. Kemler, Wholesale Paper & Bags, undated (Box 4)
  - Kershenbaum, Benny/Ladies and Men’s Custom Tailoring/advertising card, undated (Box 4)
  - Kingswood Market (Morris Borstein), undated (Box 4)
  - Kramer, Chas. (Clothing), undated (Box 4)
  - Kurzmack Variety store (Mandel Kurzmack), undated (Box 4)
  - Labinger & Gerstein Dress Factory, see also H. Gerstein, undated (Box 4)
  - Lappen & Gordon Co. (Lappen’s Fireside Center), undated (Box 4)
  - L. Laschever the Tailor (Louis Laschever), undated (Box 4)
  - Lechowetsky, Morris, chicken market, undated (Box 4)
  - Levenson Watchmaker Supplies (Morris Levenson), undated (Box 4)
  - Libman, Morris, clothing, undated (Box 4)
  - E. Lieblick Union Bakery, undated (Box 4)
- Photo Series V: Business & Professions Photographs: M-P
  - M & S Tamale Co. (Joseph Hirshfeld), undated (Box 5)
  - Margolis Cabinet Shop, 2 folders, undated (Box 5)
  - Marholin's Furniture, undated (Box 5)
  - Market Street Barbershop (Joseph Kovarsky) [folder missing, 9/16/10], undated (Box 5)
  - Markowitz Store on Main Street /Emlargment in drawer [folder missing, 9/16/10], undated (Box 5)
  - S. Max furs (Max Sklarinsky), undated (Box 5)
  - J. Max Furrier (Jacob Max), undated (Box 5)
    Max, Jacob, Furrier
  - Maxwell Drug Co., undated (Box 5)
  - Mayer, W. Tin and Agate Ware Peddler, undated (Box 5)
  - Mayflower Laundry & Dry Cleaning (Pinney Katz), undated (Box 5)
  - Meister Clothing Cleaner (M.P. Meister), undated (Box 5)
  - Merchants Ice Co. (Barney Myers), undated (Box 5)
  - I.S. Missal Dry goods, undated (Box 5)
  - Moshinsky Groceries (Nathan Moshinsky), undated (Box 5)
  - Neiman, Mendel, fruit Peddler, undated (Box 5)
  - Nelson’s Drug Store (Sam Nelson), undated (Box 5)
  - New England Leaf Tobacco, undated (Box 5)
  - Newton Robinson Store on Asylum, "Morris on ladder", undated (Box 5)
  - O.K. Bakery, undated (Box 5)
  - Parkville Apparel (Max Greenspoon), undated (Box 5)
    Greenspoon, Max, Retail, Store Owner
  - Parkway Delicatessen (Benjamin and Samuel Neistat), undated (Box 5)
  - Pierce Pharmacy, undated (Box 5)
  - Phoenix Building News, 1963-1985; photograph 1960s
  - Platt Delicatessen, undated (Box 5)
  - Produce, Unidentified, undated (Box 5)
  - Pyne-Davidson Printing Co. M. H. Davidson), undated (Box 5)
- Photo Series VI: Business & Professions Photographs: R-Z
  - Rabinovitz Soda Bottling Plant, undated (Box 6)
  - Robbins Delicatessen (Speedy Cohen), undated (Box 6)
  - Rundbaken Real Estate, undated (Box 6)
  - S. Kinder restaurant, Lender family, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Savitt, Frank/Jewelry, undated (Box 6)
  - Spaien's Department Store (Herman Spaien), undated (Box 6)
  - B. Schwartz (Beer & Ale), undated (Box 6)
  - Shoor Bros., undated (Box 6)
  - Stern & Mandlebaum, undated (Box 6)
  - Susselman Store, undated (Box 6)
  - Tager, Max, barber, undated (Box 6)
  - Torchinsky, Abraham, groceries, undated (Box 6)
  - William Toubman 7 sons Garage, undated (Box 6)
  - Tuckel's Radio Store, undated (Box 6)
  - Union Bakery (Baggish Family), undated (Box 6)
  - S. Vogel Groceries, undated (Box 6)
  - Wald butcher Shop, undated (Box 6)
  - Washington Tailor Shop, undated (Box 6)
  - Wayside Print Ship (Louis Elovich), undated (Box 6)
  - Weiner Bros. Produce, undated (Box 6)
  - Whalen Drug, undated (Box 6)
  - Whalen Drug/enlargement in drawer, undated (Box 6)
  - White Star Market (Abraham Krugman), undated (Box 6)
  - Wise-Smith & Co., undated (Box 6)
  - Woodland Meat Market, kosher (Powers), undated (Box 6)
  - Yellin's Saloon (Mayer Yellin), undated (Box 6)
  - Zucker Furniture (Max Zucker), undated (Box 6)
- Photo Series VII: Business & Professions Photographs: Oversized
  - OVERSIZE/American Coal, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Bonner & Preston Co., undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Big Lion, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Cantarow's Pharmacy, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Cheap John, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Davison Scrap, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Fisher's Ladies Apparal, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/R. Ballerstine, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/G. Fox & Co. fire, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Harris Pharmacy, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Hoffman Brothers, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Holz Portrait Studio, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Kahn's Store, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Kahn's Store, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Labinger and Gerstein, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Margolis Furniture, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Max Furs, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Nelson's Drug Store, undated (Box 7)
  - OVERSIZE/Stern & Mandlebaum, undated (Box 7)